We are out here at the 2026 NFL owners
meetings. I am joined by Vikings
executive vice president of football
operations Rob Brzezinski. And Rob,
first of all, before we get started,
this has been owners meetings number
This is your
This is year 34 for me. I don't remember
the first year I actually came down to
owners meetings, but it's been a pretty
good run. It has been. How has it
changed with your
with your with your acting role right
now? Well, I got to do some media. I
mean, this is
>> Oh, that is true. That is so [laughter]
true.
I know it's your favorite. No, no, it's
not. It's been great. I mean, this time
of year is always busy and there's a lot
going on, you know, from a roster
standpoint and and and all those things
we're typically dealing with and
obviously a little bit more this year,
but everything is going really well so
far. Well, speaking of
the Vikings announced they intend to
exercise Jordan Addison's fifth-year
option.
What's the thought process behind that
move? I mean, Jordan is a really, really
good young player.
>> [music]
>> Really, really good person. We're
excited to have him. You know, it's part
of the process in the CBA.
>> [music]
>> And I think we have until May 3rd, you
know, to actually make that official,
but for sure, you know, we intend to do
that. Yeah, I mean, you're working
[music] hard behind the scenes and in
all the meeting rooms as well. But you
also had a busy free agency period. And
when we spoke the last time, you
mentioned how you wanted to be
intentional. How do you think that
played out to what you hoped it would
be? Yeah, I think we set out to do, you
know, a few things and
I think we executed as we had hoped. You
know, there's always curveballs and and
things along the way that
don't go exactly as planned, but I'm
really proud of the discipline we've had
and we've been talking about really
trying to stack good decisions and not
try to force anything and I think we
feel really good about how our team is
positioned for 2026, you know, and the
future. Yeah, I don't I don't know if
enough people have been talking about
some some of your moves specifically in
cornerback James Pierre. What did you
guys see in him that you thought he'd be
a good fit for this Viking [music]
secondary? I mean, our our personnel
staff, our coaching staff, they just saw
traits in him
>> [music]
>> that he's going to fit Flo's defense
really, really well. And that's the the
great thing with Flo is and his staff,
they know exactly, you know, what
they're looking for in players. And then
there's alignment with the you know,
with our scouting staff and and able to
to hunt for those guys and and find a
guy like James that we're really excited
to be able to add. How do you feel like
you guys executed on your vision for a
more competitive quarterback room?
>> I don't think we could be any happier
with our quarterback room. I mean, to
bring in a talent like Kyler Murray, I
don't even know. There's there's that
speaks for itself.
A sneaky, really exciting, you know,
return for us was Carson Wentz.
You know, the we think the world of him.
And then, you know, J.J. McCarthy and
and we got Max Brosmer in the room. So,
we love the way that room looks like
right now and and there's going to be
some good competition and you know, it's
exciting. So, we are a month away from
the NFL draft. Vikings go on the clock
at number 18, but you do have nine picks
as of right now. How do you see that
flexibility helping you throughout all
the decisions you'll be making around
that time? Well, there's still a ways to
go in the process. There's still another
3 weeks of draft meetings and you know,
information is still coming in from pro
days and you know, with the college
guys. And so, the answers to the test to
some extent are still out there. So, we
still have to continue to work through
our process and
get our board stacked objectively so we
can make good decisions when we're on
the clock. And I think if you do that,
>> [music]
>> you got a great chance to be successful.
Want to let you all know a little bit
more about your draft philosophy
specifically.
How open are you to moves or trades?
Well, I mean, it's not like I think it's
an organizational philosophy, you know,
and and there are some things that we've
talked about internally about how we're
going to navigate that. And I think
number one is you got to get you want to
get your picks right. And then, kind of
next level is you can maneuver around
the board a little bit and you know,
pick up some extra capital here or there
and and and we have
some guardrails as far as how we want to
do that, but we're focused on making
sure we get our picks right. How have
you seen yourself balance the best
player available versus your biggest
position of need when you are on the
clock? I mean, I think it's the the the
biggest reason why a lot of players fail
in this business. And it's not just the
player, it's it's it's it's complicit
with the club is you force your need and
for a lot of reasons it it doesn't work
out and you you pass on a
player of higher ability for a position
of need. Puts undue pressure on the
player and there's various other factors
and you know, I may be may be old
school.
But if you get your board set right and
you kind of look for the best player
available, I think that's going to lead
you down the right path.
>> Yeah. Well, again, on a more personal
note, when the Vikings go on the clock
at 18 or wherever they do
in the draft room, it'll be a much
different feeling for you. How What do
you think it's going to be like? You
know what? Once you get in the draft
room, like the the hay is all in the
barn and it's kind of this unveiling of
how you think [snorts] it's going to,
you know, kind of come to fruition and
and and what happens and and
the trail winds a little bit, but you
know, for the most part, we're going to
be prepared and we're going to let the
draft come to us and and just excited
the way everybody's
working together. Everybody in our
organization has been stepping up in a
big way and uh
we're just we're ready to go. Yeah, no
extra added pressure now that, you know,
you get to make the call, put the pick
in.
>> No, we'll make we'll go through this
process together and like I said, I
think these these selections will be
pretty obvious, you know, each time
we're on the clock. Love that. Thank you
so much, Rob. Enjoy your rest of your
time in Phoenix.